

**Software Engineer** 

# Amad ud din

Lahore, Pakistan

+92 333 4949086

Skype: kristen.hayke amad.aud@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/amad-ud-din

https://www.hackerrank.com/amad aud

https://stackoverflow.com/users/6085791/maadi

**About** 

Experienced, forward-looking Software Engineer with 5+ years of experience developing and implementing cutting-edge software solutions to improve corporate productivity. From concept to development and delivery, I have extensive experience in all aspects of the software development lifecycle. Having a good experience in developing highly scale-able products.

## **Experience**

### Hailu Tech Pvt / Team Lead & Fullstack developer

July 2019 - PRESENT, Lahore

Hailu Tech Pvt is a China based start up company. Here, I joined it as project manager and full stack developer. My main responsibilities are:

- Designing and implementing infrastructure and application hardening methodologies (Servers, Storage, Network, Data Stores, Endpoints, Users).
- Worked and trained the team of front-end web developers on the cutting edge technology of front end framework (Angular 10)
- Worked on Design and implementation of back-end(Django).
- Assess the growth of web and mobile(ios, android) applications.

#### **Septem System /** Fullstack developer

August 2018 - July 2019, Lahore

Septem Systems is a product based software house. I joined it as a full stack developer and my core responsibilities were:

- Develop product back-end side in Python(Django).
- Core member for front-end team (Angular 8, Vue.js, Reactjs)
- Develop Cloud from IAAS using Docker and Docker Swarm.

## **Brainplow** / Fullstack developer

April 2017 - August 2019, Lahore

Brainplow is a product and project based startup company. I joined it as a full stack developer and it was my first company where I took the start of my career. My core responsibilities were:

- Back-end (Django, Flask, Go).
- Front-end (Angular 2+, reactis)
- Develop Cloud from IAAS using Docker and Docker Swarm.

## **Projects**

StartupTree / [Django, ReactJS, PostgreSQL, Docker, Linux, EC2, S3, Lambda, Elastic Search, Material, Redux, Redis, Javascript, Typescript, Cognito, Sentry]

April 2021 - Present

StartupTree is the only proven all-in-one solution for your team to effortlessly take charge of your network, events, opportunities, and reporting. Startup Tree gives university entrepreneurship programs all of the tools they require in a single package to grow their presence - all without making life complicated for the team.

**Hiwac.com** / [Django, Git, Angular 10, Typescript, Postgresql, Linux (Ubuntu), EC2, S3, CloudFront, Charts.js, Google charts. Postman, S3, Bootstrap, Grafana]

July 2019 - Jan 2022

Hiwac is a next generation end to end import and export solution for the business community. This application is made using cutting edge technologies e.g Angular 8, Django & Python. My core responsibilities in this product are to make the product modules from scratch to end and manage the respective teams.

**bridgeportclaims.com** / [Django, Angular 8, MySQL, Redis, Azure, Sockets]

January 2018 - July 2019

'bridgeportclaims.com' is a web application designed for the patient claims system in Ohio(US). The sole purpose of this application was to maintain records of claims for a patient and then complete a whole procedure from start to end. I have worked as a front-end developer in this giant health project.

**Shopnroar.com** / [Angular 2+, Django, Python, Charts.js, Google charts. Postman, S3, Bootstrap]

April 2017 - August 2018

SHOPnROAR is a next generation artificially intelligent comparative Online Shopping Engine where consumers can search for and compare millions of Products for the ultimate comparative shopping experience. SHOPnROAR assists consumers in researching and buying desired products at the cheapest price online from top and

trusted stores. SHOPnROAR helps the consumer purchase the desired product with the best reviews at the lowest price possible.

Education

**FAST - (NUCES) / BSCS** [3.45] 2013 - 2017

Awards

Prime Minister Fully Funded Scholarship (PMNICT) [2013 - 2017]

Skills

**Django (DRFW, Sockets, Chanels),** Python (NLP, Regression), Uni Test, Selenium, Django Factory Boy, Postgresql, Redis, Templates

**Angular 10** (Typescript, Angular Universal, Ivy, Socket.io), WebRTC, (Audio, video calling & Screen Sharing), Lazy loading

ReactJS, NextJS, Material UI. Bootstrap 4. HTML, CSS, JQuery

**AWS**(Conginito, S3, EC2, Lamda, Elastic Search, cloudformation, cloud front, cloud watch, SNS, SQS) Docker, Docker Swarm

Google Cloud Services, Heroku, Stripe, JIRA, Trello, Grafana, Tencent Cloud, Sentry, Mailchimp